A Guide to the University of Virginia Library Reference Department Correspondence Files,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Library Reference Department Correspondence Files
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-12/8/4.061
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These files were transferred to Special Collections from the Reference Department and accessioned on November 17, 2006.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the correspondence files of the University of Virginia Library Reference Department, ca. 1906, 1927-1980, ca. 1,200 items (4 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1.5 linear feet), chiefly topical files concerning reference questions answered by staff.
Contents List
- Albemarle County: Government, 1928 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Alderman Library: Barrett Library, 1968 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Alderman Library: Reference: Guide to British Documents and Records, 1972 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Alderman Library: Western Addition, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Alderman Newspapers: Foreign, 1969 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Alderman Press, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Association of Research Libraries (ARL): 1963 Meeting (July), 1963 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Association of Research Libraries (ARL): Committee on Microfilming Dissertations, 1964 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Association of Research Libraries (ARL): Master Microfilms, n.d. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Association of Research Libraries (ARL): Report: January 31, 1955, 1955 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Association of Research Libraries (ARL): Statistics, 1962/3, 1963 (Box-folder 1:11)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL), 1960-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): Bibliographical Project, 1965, n.d. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): Foreign Newspapers, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): Microfilm Holdings, 1965 (Box-folder 1:15)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): Serial Desiderata in the Southeast, 1964 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): "Serials Needed in Southeastern Research Libraries," 1965 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL): Strength of Collections, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Austin Family: Genealogy, 1932 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Bridgewater College, 1964 (Box-folder 1:20)
- Bowers, Fredson T., 1964-1967, 1984 (Box-folder 1:21)
- Boyd, Thomas Jefferson, 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1:22)
- Bristol, Roger P., 1955-1963, n.d. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Byrd, Williams II (of Westover), 1930-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Canada: A Short History of Canada for Americans, 1947 (Box-folder 1:25)
- Casteen, John Thomas III, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1:26)
- Christmas Cards, 1966-1970, n.d. (Box-folder 1:27)
- Cocke, John Hartwell, 1938, 1945 (Box-folder 1:28)
- D'Arcy Paul Memorial Fund, 1944 (Box-folder 1:29)
- Dabney, Charles William, 1930-1935, 1959 (Box-folder 1:30)
- Dalton, Jack, 1948-1972 (Box-folder 1:31)
- Deal, Harvey, 1954-1968 (Box-folder 2:1)
- Deal Review, 1963 (Box-folder 2:2)
- Department Libraries, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Deposit Library: Virginia, 1949 (Box-folder 2:4)
- Essay and General Literature Index: Colburn, 1960, 1965 (Box-folder 2:5)
- Flowers and Gardens-18th Century, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 2:6)
- Frantz, Ray, 1955, 1967 (Box-folder 2:7)
- Grants, 1957, 1965 (Box-folder 2:8)
- Greenway, Dr. James, 1942 (Box-folder 2:9)
- Gothic Novels, 1968-1975 (Box-folder 2:10)
- Haynes, Donald R., 1964-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 2:11)
- Higher Education Act, 1965-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Houghton, Herbert Pierrepont, 1959, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 2:13)
- Howell, Isabel, 1960 (Box-folder 2:14)
- Hudson, William Alexander, 1930 (Box-folder 2:15)
- Hutter, Edward S., 1971 (Box-folder 2:16)
- Institute of Public Affairs, 1951-1980 (Box-folder 2:17)
- Keyes, Frances Parkinson, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 2:18)
- Kilpatrick, James J., 1959-1962 (Box-folder 2:19)
- Lee, Richard Henry, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 2:20)
- Lee, Robert E., 1928-1931,1961-1966 (Box-folder 2:21)
- Loyalty Investigations, 1950 (Box-folder 2:22)
- Maddox Family, 1931 (Box-folder 2:23)
- Martin, Margaret, 1960, n.d. (Box-folder 2:24)
- Mauzy Family, 1933 (Box-folder 2:25)
- New English Dictionary, 1963 (Box-folder 2:26)
- Old Whitey, 1955, n.d. (Box-folder 2:27)
- Palmer, Forrest, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 2:28)
- Parmenter, Mr. Ross, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2:29)
- Percy, Alfred, 1949 (Box-folder 2:30)
- Pollock Family, 1931 (Box-folder 2:31)
- Preston, Margaret Junkin, 1937 (Box-folder 2:32)
- Select List of Recent Acquisitions, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 2:33)
- Shannon, E.F., n.d. (Box-folder 2:34)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA), 1954, 1962 (Box-folder 2:35)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Board Member Representative from Virginia, 1964 (Box-folder 2:36)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Church, Atlanta Meeting, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 2:37)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): College and University Section, 1964 (Box-folder 2:38)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Committee on Committees, 1961 (Box-folder 2:39)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Conference, 1962, 1962 (Box-folder 2:40)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Conference October 28, 1964, 1964 (Box-folder 2:41)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Handbook, 1963 (Box-folder 2:42)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Meeting, October 1964, 1964 (Box-folder 2:43)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Nominating Committee: 1964, 1964 (Box-folder 2:44)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Nomination Committee: Cheney, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3:1)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Norfolk, 1964, 1964 (Box-folder 3:2)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): October 1958 meeting, 1958 (Box-folder 3:3)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Public Library Reference Survey, 1956-1961 (Box-folder 3:4)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Recruiting, 1962 (Box-folder 3:5)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Reference Services, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3:6)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): RSD, 1964 (Box-folder 3:7)
- Southern Library Association (SLA): The Southeastern Librarian, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 3:8)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Statistics: College and University, 1964 (Box-folder 3:9)
- Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Union Newspaper List, 1962 (Box-folder 3:10)
- Spooner Family, University of Virginia, 1950 (Box-folder 3:11)
- "Sporting Olio," 1967 (Box-folder 3:12)
- Steqall (Steaquall) Family, 1931-1932, n.d. (Box-folder 3:13)
- Stoddard, Elizabeth, 1967, n.d. (Box-folder 3:14)
- Stone, Edward L., 1932-1938 (Box-folder 3:15)
- Student Library Committee: 1961-1962, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 3:16)
- Tetley, Gerard, 1959 (Box-folder 3:17)
- Taylor, Dr. Adrian Stevenson, 1906, 1930 (Box-folder 3:18)
- University of Virginia: Art, 1961-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 3:19)
- University of Virginia Dormitories: Books, 1966 (Box-folder 3:20)
- University of Virginia: History, 1932-1948 (Box-folder 3:21)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Table of Contents, 1980 (Box-folder 3:22)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 1, 1980 (Box-folder 3:23)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 2, 1980 (Box-folder 3:24)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 3, 1980 (Box-folder 3:25)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 4, 1980 (Box-folder 3:26)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 5, 1980 (Box-folder 3:27)
- University of Virginia Medical Center: Master Plan: Chapter 6, 1980 (Box-folder 3:28)
- University of Virginia: Strike, 1970 (Box-folder 4:1)
- Vietnam Moratorium, 1969, 1969 (Box-folder 4:2)
- Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers (Exhibits Space: Monticello Hotel, October 19-21), 1964 (Box-folder 4:3)
- Virginia Imprints, 1932 (Box-folder 4:4)
- Virginia Library Association (VLA) for Southeastern Library Association (SELA): Norfolk Public Library, 1964 (Box-folder 4:5)
- Virginia Manuscripts: Contemporary, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 4:6)
- Ward, Douglas S., 1950-1962, n.d. (Box-folder 4:7)
- Watkins, Maurine D., 1972 (Box-folder 4:8)
- Watts, Thomas Hill, 1961 (Box-folder 4:9)
- Williams, Joy, 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 4:10)
- Women, Status of (University Report), 1974 (Box-folder 4:11)
- William and Mary, College of: Publications, 1943, 1948, n.d. (Box-folder 4:12)
- Wren, Christopher, 1935-1961, n.d. (Box-folder 4:13)
- Wyant Family, 1963, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 4:14)
- Wythe County, Virginia, 1936-1955 (Box-folder 4:15)